Preliminary Inventory of the William J. Losh papers
Hoover Institution Archives
William J. Losh papers
1917-1967
75023
Losh, William J., 1896-1973
6 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (3.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diaries, correspondence, photographs, memorabilia, and printed matter, relating to the American Ambulance Service in France and Albania during World War I; the Polish legation in the United States, 1920-1921; Polish ambassador Casimir Lubomirski; the John Scopes trial in Dayton, Tennessee, 1925; and American politics during the Harding and Coolidge administrations.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American journalist; member, American Ambulance Service, 1917-1919; secretary, Polish legation in the United States, 1920-1921.
Scope and Content Note
Diaries, correspondence, photographs, memorabilia, and printed matter, relating to the American Ambulance Service in France and Albania during World War I; the Polish legation in the United States, 1920-1921; Polish ambassador Casimir Lubomirski; the John Scopes trial in Dayton, Tennessee, 1925; and American politics during the Harding and Coolidge administrations.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Lubomirski, Casimir.; Scopes, John.; American Field Service.; United States. Army. Ambulance Service.; World War, 1914-1918--Medical care.; Poland--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Poland.; World War, 1914-1918--Medical care.; United States--Politics and government--1921-1923.; United States--Politics and government--1923-1929.
Occupations
Journalists.
Container List
- American Ambulance Service (Box 1)
  - 1916-1919
  - 1917-1963
  - 1917-1969
  - 1920-1966
- American Field Service
  - General, 1917-1964
  - Scholarships, 1948-1949
- Arm strap and identification tags, n.d.
- Biographical file, 1916-1964
- Clippings, 1916-1918 (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - General
    - 1919-1924
    - 1925-1968
    - Lee, John, 1939
    - Losh, Frank A. (father), 1917-1919
    - Losh, Frank, Mrs. (mother)
      - 1917
        - February-June
        - July-December
      - 1918
        - January-July
        - August-December (Box 3)
      - 1919
- Diaries, 1917-1918
- French Army, 1917-1920
- Invitations, certificates, business cards, 1920-1930
- Invitations, certificates, business cards, 1920-1930 (Box 4)
- Knickerbocker Theater disaster, 1922 January
- Lubomirski, Casimir, 1919-1920
- Maps, 1901-1918
- Maps, 1901-1918 (Box 5)
- Moutoux, John, 1926-1970
- Photographs, n.d.
- Polish Legation in Washington, D.C., 1920-1926
- Stanford University, 1915-1950 (Box 6)
- United Press, 1924-1971
- U.S. Army Ambulance Service Association, 1941
- World War I, 1914-1925
- Miscellany, 1923-1924
- Scrapbooks (Box 7)
  - William Losh's activities as United Press journalist, 1923-1925
  - Various materials relating to William Losh, 1925-1973
- Photo album depicting people and scenes in Europe and the Middle East, 1917-1918 (Box 8)